You can kill a revolutionary but you can't kill the revolution.
Judas and the Black Messiah is a drama, history film directed by Shaka King.
Bill O'Neal infiltrates the Black Panthers on the
orders of FBI Agent Mitchell and J.
Edgar Hoover.
As Black Panther Chairman Fred Hampton ascends—falling for a fellow
revolutionary en route—a battle wages for O’Neal’s soul.
Fred Hampton, played by Daniel Kaluuya.
Bill O'Neal, played by LaKeith Stanfield.
Roy Mitchell, played by Jesse Plemons.
Deborah Johnson, played by Dominique Fishback.
Jimmy Palmer, played by Ashton Sanders.
Jake Winters, played by Algee Smith.
Judas and the Black Messiah is a 2021 biographical historical crime drama film directed and produced by Shaka King,
who wrote the screenplay with Will Berson, based on a story by the pair and Kenny and Keith Lucas.
The film is about the betrayal of Fred Hampton (played by Daniel Kaluuya), chairman of the Illinois chapter of the Black
Panther Party in late 1960s Chicago, by William O'Neal (played by LaKeith Stanfield), an FBI informant.
Jesse Plemons, Dominique Fishback, Ashton Sanders, Darrell Britt-Gibson, Lil Rel
Howery, Algee Smith, Dominique Thorne, and Martin Sheen also star.
A Fred Hampton biopic had been in the works for several years, with the Lucas brothers
and Will Berson writing and shopping screenplays individually since 2014.
Berson's version almost got made with F.
Gary Gray directing, but King was hired to direct when that fell through.
The cast joined in 2019, with the blessings of Hampton's
family, with filming beginning that fall in Ohio.
Judas and the Black Messiah premiered at the 2021 Sundance Film Festival on
February 1, 2021, and was released in the United States by Warner Bros.
Pictures on February 12, simultaneously in theaters and digitally on HBO Max.
Released amid the COVID-19 pandemic, the film grossed $7
million worldwide against a budget of $26 million.
The film was acclaimed by critics, who praised King's direction, the cinematography, the screenplay,
the performances (particularly Kaluuya, Stanfield, and Fishback), and its timely themes.
The film earned six Oscar nominations at the 93rd Academy Awards, including Best Picture and Best Supporting Actor
for Stanfield, winning Best Supporting Actor (Kaluuya) and Best Original Song ("Fight for You").
For his performance, Kaluuya also won Best Supporting Actor at the Golden Globes,
Critics' Choice Awards, Screen Actors Guild Awards, and BAFTA Awards.
Since its release, Judas and the Black Messiah  has been
cited as one of the best films of the 2020s.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, assassination,
black panther party, based on true story, betrayal.
The tone is emotional.